Montgomery, Texas 77316 M:936.520.3343

michaelryanitprofessional@outlook.com http://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelryanitpro/

OBJECTIVE

Experienced customer centric consultant seeking an IT Cloud Professional Services position.

SUMMARY

A highly-experienced customer-centric information technology professional with a focus on customer satisfaction while providing practical solutions leveraging his business and IT expertise. Determined to promote cloud computing to businesses of all sizes. Background in developing projects with the goal of new market penetration. Experienced at working independently, remote and in a multi-country team environment.

- Saved Hewlett-Packard over \$1,000,000 in R&D operational expense and contributed \$100,000+ in Professional Services revenue with a custom integration using new technology for an Enterprise Output Management product.
- Saved Hewlett-Packard an estimated \$1,000,000 in future support cost during negotiations on a \$110,000,000 managed services contract with the largest US bank by recognizing two key issues.

CRITICAL SKILLS

- Trusted Advisor
- C#, .NET Framework(s)
- Enterprise software implementation
- ASP.NET. ADO.NET
- Java, OSGi
- C, C++
- Git, GitHub, TFS
- JavaScript
- XML, JSON
- MySQL, Oracle
- SQL Server, IBM DB2
- WebSphere
- Oracle Weblogic

- Cloud AWS S3, EC2, RDS(MySql)
- Windows 10/2016
- Ubuntu
- Red Hat Enterprise
- SUSE Enterprise Server
- Apple OSX / iOS
- Google Android
- Docker
- HAProxy, NGINX
- IIS, Tomcat, TomEE, **JBoss**
- Perl, Python

- **Eclipse**
- Ant, Maven, Gradle
- Visual Studio 2017, 2015
- JIRA, HP Quality Center
- Jenkins, CircleCl
- **Entity Framework**
- Hypervisors VMware, Microsoft, Oracle
- Agile, Waterfall
- HP-UX, Solaris, AIX
- Bootstrap, CSS
- Custom Enterprise software integration solutions

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MTR Consulting Montgomery, Texas

Senior Business IT Consultant

2014 to Current

- Trusted advisor role mentoring businesses on risk mitigation, planning, allocation of IT resources including the effective increase in profits with the use of Cloud based resources.
- Lead Architect/Developer adopted an unfinished eCommerce web site mid-development, upgraded various libraries, established logging, rearchitected design from web forms to layer design with the desired platform to be MVC for a \$28,000,000 finance company with an aggressive growth plan to be \$100,000,000 in 4 years.
- Lead Architect/Consultant providing business and IT services for Risk Mitigation, eCommerce, VPN, managing IT assets, repair hardware, and providing custom integration for industry specific software for a startup \$2,000,000 automotive repair and diesel performance shop.

28msec Montgomery, Texas **Senior Solutions Consultant**

2016 to 2017

Member of a startup team, working directly for the CEO, challenged with penetrating the US financial market for a SaaS based advanced data analytics and mega dimensional reporting platform. Project manager confronted with delivering on a restricted timeframe with diminishing resources for the central bank of Israel.

Pre-sales activity involving companies executing M&A efforts

- Designed and developed a custom ETL application in support of migrating the prospective customer's
 acquisition target(s) financial data into a CellStore residing in an AWS based MongoDB via REST API. The
 application featured use of the .NET Task Parallel Library significantly reducing execution duration from 4+
 hours to 8+ minutes.
- Trusted advisor to the CEO in customer contract negotiations providing perspective on strategy and tactics.

HEWLETT PACKARD Montgomery, Texas

Senior Software Designer

2009 to 2014

Member of a geographically diverse R&D team tasked with expanding a product line based on customer and market demands as well as enhancing existing products.

- Project lead for the establishment of the first private Cloud for the Enterprise Software Solutions Center.
- Empower setup and documenting on app servers, multiple configurations
- Command Center/Delivery Manager R&D Support Lead for product, development, QA work
- Engine as a Service based in AWS (EC2, Cloud Formation, S3, RDS MySql, ELB, Route53) as the production environment (used in the HP Relate product), QA work and defect resolution.
- Relate Team Lead for choosing the ui testing platform, deployment and coordinating test script development.
- Live Application Library (LAL) contributed to the product enhancement in the areas of Fulfillment, Scheduler Jobs and Workflow OSGi bundles.

Senior Principal Consultant

2002 to 2009

Senior member of the Global Document Delivery team responsible for RFP/RFI responses; requirements gathering, scoping, negotiating a SOW, pre-sales bid review, analysis, design and implementation. Collaborated with Marketing and R&D to productize the custom solutions created during my tenure.

- Lead Inventor of the inaugural web services for HP Output Server (HP Output Management Web Services -HPOMWS) to promote the elimination of maintenance costs associated with HP Output Server clients on Enterprise application servers and to ease the effort of integrating a myriad of customer's applications to HP Output Server.
 - Lead Architect/Developer for a complete SOA solution to integrate a nationwide train management dispatch system with HP Output Server including a web services based job status feedback system for the second largest Class I North American railroad in less than 7 weeks.
 - Lead Architect/Developer for a SOA solution to accept job file size of 2 GB for the integration between a ship building system and HP Output Server including a web services based job status feedback system for one of the largest naval ship building defense contractors.
- Lead Architect/Developer for a prototype integration between HP Output Server and HP Universal Print Driver.
- Lead Architect/Developer for a custom enterprise integration between Ariba Buyer and HP Output Server utilizing Microsoft COM and Java to COM bridge technology for a major Pharmaceutical company.
- Lead Architect/Developer for a custom inbound fax solution to route faxes using HP Output Server for one of the largest energy producing/transportation companies located on the east coast of the US.
- Lead Architect/Developer for a custom enterprise integration between Siebel Systems and HP Output Server for a major pharmaceutical company located on the east coast of the US.

Technical Liaison 2004 to 2007

Key technical member of a cross divisional team, commissioned with creating a new Document Capture product/service line of business.

- Lead technical SME for responding to RFPs/RFIs including customer and conference presentations.
- Key role as a trusted advisor responsible for providing leadership in projects, during pre-sales or post-sales activities including customer escalations requiring on site resolution.
- Lead Consultant for Job Accounting, LAN Fax, Digital Sending document delivery software applications for the HP Document Capture line of business.

COMPAQ COMPUTER CORPORATION Houston, Texas **Systems/Software Engineer V**

1996 to 2002

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, Illinois State University, Normal, Illinois